Guide to the Glad Day Press publications, 1967-1973
Glad Day Press publications, 1967-1973
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Glad Day Press records, 1967-1973.
2961
Glad Day Press.
1.2 cubic ft.
Handbills, serials, photographs, newsletters, publications, drafts of articles and speeches, and a calendar.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Handbills and serials published by Glad Day Press, including material concerning the Vietnam War, the Black Liberation Movement, Students for a Democratic Society (SDS); and the Cornell University Carpenter Hall takeover, May 1972. Serials include Caw! and New Left Notes (both published by the SDS), Mobilizer, Cornell-Ithaca Mobilizer, The First Issue, Workers Bulletin, Watu (published by The Black Literary Society of Cornell University), Dateline: Ithaca, New Patriot, Volunteers, Tiohero, and Notes from a Green Piano. Also, photographs, newsletters, publications, drafts of articles and speeches, and a calendar.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Glad Day Press, Ithaca, New York, printed left-wing material during the 1960s and 1970s.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Handbills and serials published by Glad Day Press, including material concerning the Vietnam War, the Black Liberation Movement, Students for a Democratic Society (SDS); and the Cornell University Carpenter Hall takeover, May 1972. Serials include Caw! and New Left Notes (both published by the SDS), Mobilizer, Cornell-Ithaca Mobilizer, The First Issue, Workers Bulletin, Watu (published by The Black Literary Society of Cornell University), Dateline: Ithaca, New Patriot, Volunteers, Tiohero, and Notes from a Green Piano. Also, photographs, newsletters, publications, drafts of articles and speeches, and a calendar.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Glad Day Press.; Black Literary Society of Cornell University.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.; Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.)
Titles:
Caw!.; New left notes.; Mobilizer.; Cornell-Ithaca mobilizer.; The first issue.; Workers bulletin.; Watu.; Dateline: Ithaca.; New patriot.; Volunteers.; Tiohero.; Notes from the green piano.
Subjects:
Political clubs--New York (State)--Ithaca.; College students--Political activity.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975.; Radicalism.; Student movements.
Form and Genre Terms:
Handbills.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Political handbills and serial publications
  - New China Study Group, Vol. I, No.1-3, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Worker's Bull (LH1 W93+), Vol. I, No. 1-4, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Open House, No. 3, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Guava Jelly (LH1 G91++), 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - SDS = SS, Vol. I, No. 1-3, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mayday (LH1 M46++), Vol. I, No. 1-3, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Watu, (LH1 W35+), Vol. I, III, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Watu, Vol. IV, No. 1; Vol. V, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Watu, Vol. VI, VII, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Watu, Vol. VIII, X, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Year One, No. 1-5, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ithaca SDS, Miscellaneous Handbills (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - New Left Notes, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mobilizer, Vol I, No. 1-3; Vol. III, No. 1, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Ithaca Mobilizer, Vol. (Week) I-IV, XI, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - First Issue, No. 1-5, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - First Issue, No. 6-8, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - First Issue, 9-12, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dateline Ithaca, No. 1-25, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dateline Ithaca, No. 26-50, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dateline Ithaca, No. 51-75, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dateline Ithaca, No. 76-100, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dateline Ithaca, No. 101-103, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Tiohero, Vol. I, No. 1-4, 6, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Tiohero, Vol. II, No. 1-3, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cornell Mobe (LH1 C81 M6+), No. 1-3, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Caw!, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Volunteers (LH1 V79++), 1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Notes from the Green Piano (AP2 N91+), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Handbills, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Handbills, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Handbills, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Handbills, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Handbills and Publications, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Handbills and Publications, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mayday (LH1 M46+), Son of Cornell, (LH1 S69+); Talkin Black, (LH1 T13+);; Any Way You Want It, (LH1 A63+); 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - New Patriot, No. 1-17, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - New Patriot, No. 18-30, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - New Patriot, No. 31-40, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - New Patriot, No. 41-51, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)